raptortech.com 2015-06-07

# Raptor Technologies LLC - Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how Raptor Technologies, LLC (“we”, “us” or “RAPTOR”) collects, uses and shares personally identifiable information (“PII”) we obtain from and about individuals located in the U.S. both online and off-line. This Privacy Policy is effective as of March __, 2013. From time to time RAPTOR may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives or changes in the law, our PII collection and use practices, the features of our web sites, or technology. You should review the Privacy Policy periodically so that you are up to date on our most current policies and practices.

## COLLECTION: Collection of PII by RAPTOR

### **General.**

RAPTOR collects PII (consisting of information such as your full name, email address, mailing address or telephone number) only in order to create or enhance our relationship with you. When we collect PII from you, it is because you are voluntarily submitting the information to us in order to access our services or in connection with content or suggestions you submit to us or because you want us to furnish you with products, services or information. On those occasions when we obtain PII from a third party, we use only reputable sources of such information.

### **Cookies.**

Cookies are small bits of information that RAPTOR places on the hard drive of your computer. RAPTOR uses cookies to identify your Internet browser and to determine whether you have installed the enabling software needed to access certain material on our web site(s). However RAPTOR does not use cookies or similar tools to collect or otherwise record any type of PII provided by or about any visitor to RAPTOR. 

On occasion, RAPTOR may use cookies or similar tools to relate your use of our web site(s) to personally identifiable information obtained from you or a reputable third party. For example, if you’ve asked us to send you information about our products or services, cookies and/or other information about your online activities may allow us to limit the materials we send you to items we know you will find interesting, based on your prior online activities and preferences. You can program your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent or to refuse cookies completely. However, without cookies you may not have access to certain features on RAPTOR’s web site(s).

### **IP Addresses.**

An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you are using your browser on the Internet. The servers that serve our web site automatically identify your computer by its IP address.

## **USE: RAPTOR’s Use of PII.**

RAPTOR will use your PII in a manner that is consistent with this Policy and for the purpose for which it is submitted, unless other uses are disclosed and you allow us to use your information in other ways. Notwithstanding the foregoing, RAPTOR may use PII in aggregate, anonymous form for research purposes.

If RAPTOR obtains PII from a third party, such as a business partner, our subsequent use of this information is governed by this Policy. There may be instances when RAPTOR may disclose PII without providing you with a choice in order to protect the legal rights of RAPTOR, its producers, affiliates, parent company, employees, agents, contractors and their service providers, including to protect the safety and security of visitors to our web sites, to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes, or to comply with the law or legal process. In addition, if RAPTOR sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, RAPTOR may transfer your PII to a third party as part of that transaction.

## **SECURITY: RAPTOR Protects the Security of PII.**

RAPTOR uses reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard PII in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. In addition RAPTOR uses reasonable methods to make sure that PII is accurate, up-to-date and appropriately complete. However RAPTOR, its producers, parent company, affiliates, employees, agents, contractors and their service providers do not represent, warrant, or guarantee that PII will be protected against unauthorized access, loss, misuse or alterations. We do not accept any liability for PII submitted, or for any third parties’ use or misuse of PII. If you choose to provide PII, RAPTOR will not use the information for any purpose other than its original purpose and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## **CHILDREN: Use of the RAPTOR Web Site(s) by Children.**

### **Children Under the Age of 13.**

RAPTOR does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on RAPTOR. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at support@raptorware.com.

### **Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18.**

We recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet, including RAPTOR.

## **OTHER TERMS.**

Your use of the RAPTOR web site(s) is subject to the terms and conditions set forth herein. By accessing or using the RAPTOR web site(s), you agree to be bound by the Terms of Use in effect at the time of your access or use, including the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

## **CONTACTING US.**

You can contact us at support@raptorware.com to request access to your PII or to request that RAPTOR update or correct your PII. If you believe that RAPTOR has failed to adhere to this Privacy Policy, please contact us immediately at support@raptorware.com and ask for customer assistance.

﻿
